## **Mufeed Kamal**

Houston, TX • (214) 912-1509 • mufeedkamal@gmail.com • https://mufeedkamal.com

### **Summary**

Current Software Engineering master's student at Arizona State University, with a passion for software development. I am committed to continuous learning and aim to contribute my creativity and technical acumen to develop intuitive, user-centric applications, and websites, pushing the boundaries of digital experiences.

### **Education**

## MASTER OF SCIENCE IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING (MS)• ARIZONA STATE UNIVERSITY • 2024-

• Acquiring advanced knowledge in software development, project management, and more.

#### COURSEWORK IN PROGRAMMING • HOUSTON COMMUNITY COLLEGE • 2023 - 2023

- Obtaining pre-requisite coursework to start the MS in Software Engineering program.
- Coursework relating to Software Development methodology, control structures, objectoriented design, data structures, and recursive algorithms. Python and Java were utilized.

# MASTER OF SCIENCE IN MOLECULAR AND CELL BIOLOGY (MS) • UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS AT DALLAS • 2020 – 2021

UTD Graduate Grant Recipient

## BACHELOR OF SCEINCE IN BIOLOGY (BS) • UNIVERSITY OF HOUSTON – MAIN CAMPUS • 2016 - 2020

• UH Academic Scholarship Recipient

## **Relevant Work Experience**

## TECHNICAL SOFTWARE SUPPORT INTERN • PCS SOFTWARE • HOUSTON, TX • 09/2023 – CURRENT

- Provide prompt, courteous, and effective technical support to customers and end-users through various communication channels, such as email, phone, or chat.
- Collaborate with other support team members and cross-functional teams to resolve complex technical issues and ensure timely resolutions.
- Diagnose and troubleshoot software-related issues, identifying root causes and finding effective solutions to resolve technical problems.

#### CODING INSTRUCTOR • ICODE • PEARLAND, TX • 07/2023 - 09/2023

• Instruct students on the use of industry-standard software for graphics design, multimedia creation, web development, and various programming languages and frameworks.

- Stay updated with latest trends and advancements in coding and technology to enhance teaching content.
- Mentored and trained new interns and documented knowledge transfer for future hires.

#### GRAPHICS AND WEB DESIGNER • STUDIO ALPHA • FREELANCING • 01/2018 - 05/2021

- Building and maintaining websites and web applications using HTML, CSS, Vanilla JavaScript, PHP, Python, and WordPress.
- Implementing responsive design principles, developed and integrated content management systems (CMS) to facilitate website updates and content publishing.
- Designed wireframes and templates for websites, mobile apps, and other digital platforms.
- Created visual designs for various materials, such as but not limited to: logos, branding, brochures, posters, banners, social media graphics, and infographics.

### **Technical skills**

- Skilled in Python, JavaScript (React.js, Node.js, full-stack web development, jQuery, Bootstrap 4), HTML, CSS, SQL (MySQL), PHP, WordPress, Shopify, Firebase, Netlify, Jira, Kanban, Atlassian, Salesforce, and Confluence.
- Experienced in Figma, Sketch, Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Dreamweaver, After Effects, Premiere Pro), Final Cut Pro, CorelDraw, Blender, and Cinema4D

### **Relevant Soft Skills**

• UI/UX Research and Design, User-centered Design, Web Based Solutions, Rapid Prototyping, Data-Driven design, Small Team Experience, Graphics Design, UI testing, Web Design, Multitasking, Agile and Scrum Methodology, Software De-bugging, and Software Support.

## **Certifications**

- Scrimba Front-End Developer Career Path 07/23
- Scrimba UI Design 08/23
- Scrimba Responsive Web Design 08/23
- IE Brand and Product Management 11/22
- IBM Agile Development and Scrum 11/22
- Google Analytics Individual Qualification 11/22
- Google ads Search Certification 11/22
- Microsoft Advertising Certified Professional 11/22
- HubSpot Academy Inbound Marketing 12/22